<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Holt Dwyer</title>
    <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Holt Dwyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Farming on the Margin: the Green Revolution and Farm Sizes in India</title>
      <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/india_fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/india_fs/</guid>
      <description>I investigate the impact of the Green Revolution on the farm size distribution in India. Employing an instrument for the adoption of new high-yielding varieties of staple crops, I find that adoption of high-yielding crop varieties led to increased concentration of farms and farmland in the smallest size category, with no effects on large farms. This contrasts with the predictions of existing models of the farm size distribution, in which an increase in farmland productivity puts downward pressure on sizes across the full range of the distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Procurement Contracts on Heterogeneous Firms: Evidence from the United States</title>
      <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/firms_procurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/firms_procurement/</guid>
      <description>Work in progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose Woods are These? &#39;Maintained&#39; Forest Enforcement in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/indonesia_forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/indonesia_forest/</guid>
      <description>In this paper I investigate the effectiveness of enforcement of Indonesia&amp;rsquo;s Maintained Forest, a vast area under the control of the central government that is supposed to be maintained as forest in perpetuity. Using a geographic RD design, I find that there are only small de facto effects of this de jure protected status. Most of the small protective effect appears to operate through restrictions on tree crops, a major source of deforestation (and also local economic development) in Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralizing Development: Structural Transformation Effects of Indonesia&#39;s Village Fund</title>
      <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/village_fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/village_fund/</guid>
      <description>Can development objectives be effectively pursued by channeling resources to local governments? We investigate the effects of a large increase in resources available to rural villages on local development outcomes. Work in progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is Air: The Non-Health Effects of Air Pollution</title>
      <link>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/thisisair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holtdwyer.netlify.app/research/thisisair/</guid>
      <description>With Sandra Aguilar-Gomez, Joshua Graff Zivin, and Matthew Neidell.
A robust body of evidence shows that air pollution exposure is detrimental to health outcomes, often measured as deaths and hospitalizations. This literature has focused less on subclinical channels that nonetheless impact behavior, performance, and skills. This article reviews the economic research investigating the causal effects of pollution on &amp;ldquo;non-health&amp;rdquo; endpoints, including labor productivity, cognitive performance, and multiple forms of decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
